<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr Picnic</title>
    <link>https://dr-picnic.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr Picnic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright 2018-2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dr-picnic.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Role Playing Games</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/rpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/rpg/</guid>
      <description>I have always been passionate about imaginary worlds and great adventures. Until I was 16 years old, I spent a good part of my free time creating fantasy worlds, heroes, creatures, and imagining stories. Everything seemed destined for role-playing games, yet I only played a few games in middle and high school. I just didn&amp;rsquo;t have the people around me to play them.
Then, after watching Actual Plays, the urge to play became irresistible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Draw</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/learning-to-draw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/learning-to-draw/</guid>
      <description>In the context of Covid-19, I stayed with my parents for a few weeks, sick. I was still able to do activities for a few hours a day. So I finally decided to learn how to draw. My drawing skills have been a limitation for many of my projects, whether they are video games, board games or educational tools.
On April 6, I started a challenge to get started. I opened an account instagram on which I posted one drawing a day for 21 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cottage</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/art/illustrations/200512_cottage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/art/illustrations/200512_cottage/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Bépo</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/bepo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/bepo/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago I started having severe pain in my left wrist when I was typing all day on the keyboard. A few sessions with the osteopath made this pain disappear. However, each time I used my wrist again intensively the pains would return. After some research on the internet, I saw that people who were in the same situation as me had solved their problem by changing the layout of their keyboard to an ergonomic layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pot-au-jeu 2.0</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/game-jam-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/game-jam-2/</guid>
      <description>Last June, I participated in the second edition of the “Pot-au-jeu” game jam organized by the french Youtuber At0mium. Last year, I made a game named Paperboy Droid which was ranked second in the gameplay category. This year, I made a game named “Le mystère des pierres” (The mystery of stones). It’s a puzzle game where the player moves stones to give orders to a robot. Without knowing it, the player will learn the basic notions of programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One year later</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/one-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/one-year-later/</guid>
      <description>It has been almost a year since the last article I wrote on this blog. This year has been one of the busiest I ever had. After last year&amp;rsquo;s game jam, I decided to try going serious about making games. I asked for a part-time job and planned to make a game that could be sold within a year. This was intended to be a test to see if it would be a viable option to start making games full time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mysterious stones</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/games/the-myterious-stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/games/the-myterious-stones/</guid>
      <description>This game is an updated version of &amp;ldquo;Le mystère des pierres&amp;rdquo; (which is available only in french), a game developed for the 60 hours &amp;ldquo;Pot-au-Jeu&amp;rdquo; game jam (organized by the french youtuber At0mium).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assma</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/art/street_art/190517_assma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/art/street_art/190517_assma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hani</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/art/street_art/190517_hani_jaune/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/art/street_art/190517_hani_jaune/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hani</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/art/street_art/190517_hani_violet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/art/street_art/190517_hani_violet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Game Jam That Mattered</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/game-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/game-jam/</guid>
      <description>A bit more than two weeks ago, I took part in a game jam organized by a french Youtuber (At0mium). For those who don’t know what a game jam is, it’s basically a video game creation contest where you create a game within a short period of time. In my case, I created the game from scratch during a weekend on the theme: “Faire du neuf avec du vieux”. When I enrolled, I thought that it would be a fun experience and a small break from my current project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paperboy Droid</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/games/paperboy-droid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/games/paperboy-droid/</guid>
      <description>I created Paperboy Droid in a weekend for At0mium&amp;rsquo;s POT-AU-JEU Game Jam on the theme: Make something new with something old! Paperboy Droid is a remake of Paperboy by Tiger Electronics. This is the first game my dad gave me when I was little. I completely changed the mechanics of the game: you have to program a droid that will play for you by performing the actions of your program. I created the game alone during the game jam weekend, without using prefabricated elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great time with my family</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/great-time-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/great-time-family/</guid>
      <description>A few days after finishing Great Bee (the first game I actually released), I went to a barbecue at my wife’s family. Of course, I took my computer with the game on it. At that point, I had no idea what kind of feedback I would get. I just let them play the game.
The test started with my wife’s little sister who is in primary school. It was before dinner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Bee</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/games/great-bee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/games/great-bee/</guid>
      <description>In Great Bee, you play a bee that have to forage all the flowers in every level. The frog and the sun are your enemies. Colliding with them kills you. The sun is moving slowly, but the frog is accelerating over time. The sun can also be helpful because when it touches a flower, it will turn it into a strawberry. When you eat a strawberry, you become a super bee for a few seconds and you can slap the frog to reset its speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Bee - First game: done!</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/great-bee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/great-bee/</guid>
      <description>I just finished my first game! It&amp;rsquo;s called Great Bee. You can play it online on itch.io or download it for free. Please share it with your friends if you like it and feel free to write any feedback on the game. In Great Bee, you play a bee that have to forage all the flowers in every level. The frog and the sun are your enemies. Colliding with them kills you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PICO-8 - A Childhood Dream</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/pico-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/blog/pico-8/</guid>
      <description>I read a lot of positive reviews about the PICO-8 fantasy console. Instead of listing the good points it has, I will tell you my story with PICO-8. For those who don’t know, it is a fake console that allows making games within the console itself. This includes code, graphics, sound, music, and maps. The games can be easily shared as PNG cartridge images.
First, a little background. Short version. I started creating video games long ago and I really loved it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://dr-picnic.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dr-picnic.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been passionate about programming and what can be achieved with it since my childhood. I explored a lot of areas in software development such as 2D and 3D games, web applications, real-time and embedded software, functional programming, formal methods, machine learning, data visualization, and deployment. I started a lot of projects and I’m always working on some of them. This is what makes me feel alive: unleashing my creativity to solve new problems while making things work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>